<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hugo on 👩🏾‍🎤hello</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>👩🏾‍🎤hello (hugo)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 18:42:01 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://example.com/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Hugo Satic Site Generator</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/using-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 18:42:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/using-hugo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I recently started contributing to free and open source, but that&amp;rsquo;s a story for another day. So well I stumbled upon a bunch of projects with issues open which required help in either completely writing new documentation using &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; or migrating the existing documentation to Hugo. I was naturally curious why so many organizations were willing to make that shift. So I started my research and this is what I learnt about Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-hugo&#34;&gt;Why Hugo ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/5PSPV1ucLX31u/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Confused parrot gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll, VuePress, Gatsby, Gridsome, Hugo !!! Where does one honestly start 🤷🏾‍♀️&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well Hugo, as well as the above mentioned technologies are collectively known as static site generators. Static site generators are in layman&amp;rsquo;s terms applications which are used to create static HTML websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static websites display web content in the user&amp;rsquo;s web browser exactly as it is stored in the server. Hence every user who visits a static site interacts with exactly the same content. Whereas conversely we have dynamic websites which serve content on a user&amp;rsquo;s browser as it is generated by web applications. Web applications make use complex server-side calls which in turn enable dynamic content to be served to each and every user who visit the site if need be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static site generators work by parsing content which is normaly written in either &lt;a href=&#34;https://guides.github.com/features/mastering-markdown/&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; and/or templating languages, layouts and other meta data and then converting all the source files into HTML. Its important to appreciate that when ever there is a change in the source code, the static site generator re-builds the whole website all over again and uploads it to the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advantages of using static site generators :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better SEO: as all web content is served in simple HTML web scrapers can easily search the site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speed: there are no calls made to external databases, static sites are served preety fast in comparison to dynamic websites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved security since: static sites are independent of databases they are basically hacker proof.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo, stands out because:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Its open-source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Its incredible fast 🚀, it is the fastest static site generator to date. Hugo is written using &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Golang&lt;/a&gt;, using Go makes Hugo build processes incredible fast!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It has a wide variety of themes which make it easy to create a static website, you dont have to start from scatch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far the only cons I came across when using Hugo were that to fully harness its power you have to know Go. Knowing a little bit of Go gives you so much power in twerking up themes, which is rather important if you want to give a unique feel to your site despite it being created from a theme. I also would love to express the fact that it took me time to warp my head around how Hugo works despite coming from a solid background in front-end development. So the learning curve of learning how to use static site generators is steep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-expiriences-using-hugo&#34;&gt;My expiriences using Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My preferred method of learning a new technology is through watching video tutorials.
So for an intro to using Hugo for my personal blog I found the following video tutorials useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gSiAcyTWU3c&amp;amp;t=510s&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gSiAcyTWU3c&amp;amp;t=510s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qtIqKaDlqXo&amp;amp;list=PLLAZ4kZ9dFpOnyRlyS-liKL5ReHDcj4G3&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qtIqKaDlqXo&amp;amp;list=PLLAZ4kZ9dFpOnyRlyS-liKL5ReHDcj4G3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After going through the tutorials I followed the Hugo official &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; on getting started. It was preety easy to follow. My theme of choice was &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-theme-anubis/&#34;&gt;Anubis&lt;/a&gt;, I chose it because its styling is minimalist and clean and most importantly the styling wasn&amp;rsquo;t too opinionated I had lots of room to play around and twerk the styling without having to change a lot of the original styling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-technologies-used-in-creating-my-blog&#34;&gt;Other Technologies used in creating my blog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://formspree.io/&#34;&gt;FormSpree&lt;/a&gt; : is basically a delivery service, it collects form data and then sends email alerts when forms are submitted on static websites. Its intergration into a static website is very easy and seamless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;making-it-even-better-for-none-techies-integrating-hugo-with-cmses&#34;&gt;Making it even better for none techies | Integrating Hugo with CMSes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo can be bundled with headless content management systems like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datocms.com/&#34;&gt;DatoCMS&lt;/a&gt; to enable it to be used by users from a non-technical background. Read DatoCMS official &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datocms.com/docs/hugo&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; to find out about how that can be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>